别又来一次啊
Not again.
我刚刚才从批斗大会过来
I just came from an intervention.
不不 妮可 这是员工会议
Oh, no, no, Nicole, this is a staff meeting.
你叫我们来的
You asked us to be here.
拿着 加藤
Here you go, Kato.
对 我想跟大家
Yes, I wanted to talk to you all
说一件很重要的事
about something very important.
几百万年来哪种植物
So, what plant has been revered
因为具有愈合能力
for its healing properties
而备受尊崇
for millions of years?
芦荟[音似你好]
Aloe.
你也好呀
'ello to you, too,
但我们专心一点
but let's stay focused.
-是辣椒 -辣椒
- Peppers. - Peppers.
好奇怪 我们最近都神同步
Weird, we are so in synch these days.
我想做辣椒生意 各位
I want to be in the pepper business, people.
我现在就需要点子
And I need ideas now.
我最近几周一个产品创意都想不出来
I haven't come up with a single product idea in weeks,
所以我在公司如履薄冰
so I'm on thin ice at NERP.
这"薄冰"不是指我们网页上出售的
And I don't mean the low-calorie ice cubes
低卡冰块
we sell on our website.
我的继外婆
Well, my -- my step-grandmother,
她是哥伦比亚人
she is from Colombia,
她卖的莎莎酱
and she sells a salsa
可能就是用这些神奇的辣椒制成的
that is supposedly made with these magical peppers.
辣椒 我刚刚正好提起辣椒
Peppers? I was just talking about them.
对呀
Yeah.
我几时能跟她见面
When can I meet her?
把我的酱料生意卖给诺普
Sell my sauce business to NERP?
你应该能得到一大笔钱
I think you could get a lot for it.
妮可想要什么
When Nicole wants something,
就会砸钱去买
she just throws money at it.
她买下隔壁邻居的房子
She bought her next-door neighbor's house
就因为她喜欢他家的邮箱
because she liked the mailbox.
我不知道
I don't know.
我知道 立刻脱手
I do. Dump it.
那玩意比一个学士学位还不值钱
That thing is worth less than a bachelor's degree.
拜托了 歌洛莉亚 我真的很需要这个
Please, Gloria. I really need this.
在那办公室里没人把我当回事
No one takes me seriously at that office.
我连自己的隔间都没有
I don't even have my own cubicle.
我跟实习生们共用一张巨大的豆袋椅
I share one, giant bean bag chair with the interns.
我想帮你
I want to help you,
但 有什么感觉不对
but...something feels wrong.
你先去见个面 听听她给你开的条件
Just go to the meeting and hear what the offer is.
好吧 我会去 我会听
Okay, fine. I will go. I will listen.
但我不会卖掉的
But I am not selling.
-你觉得呢 -会很难办
- What do you think? ?- It's gonna be tough.
她有过大量卖不出这辣酱的练习
She's got a lot of practice not selling that sauce.
你怎么穿西装外套配T恤
Whoa, what's up with the blazer and the t-shirt?
你是要去参加大学面试
Thought you were going to a college interview,
不是去1988年表演单口相声吧
not doing stand up in 1988.
我开始觉得上大学也许不适合我
I'm starting to think maybe college isn't for me.
俱乐部里有个人说我也许可以当模特
There's this guy at the club who said I could be a model.
他说这礼拜要带我到沙漠里去
He said he's gonna take me out to the desert this week
拍几张照片
and take some pictures.
我劝你三思
I'd put a pin in that.
你当然要去读大学了
Of course you're going to college.
你在说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我说不好
I don't know.
以前读书的时候我就成绩一直不好
I wasn't very good at school the first time around.
也许我就是...
Maybe I'm just --
不许你说自己是白痴
Hey! Don't you dare call yourself "an idiot".
我没要这么说
I wasn't going to.
我是想说 "也许我就是还没准备好"
I was gonna say, "maybe I'm not ready."
亲爱的 你只是怯场了
Honey, it's just nerves.
改变是很吓人的 但最终
Change is scary, but in the end,
我保证 一切都是值得的
I promise, it is all worth it.
你妈妈说得对
Your mother's right.
你拼尽全力 使出浑身解数
You dig deep, you make your best effort,
-就能找到荣誉 -没错
- that's where you find the glory. - Exactly.
就像那次我在赛跑中战胜她一样
Like that time I beat her in that race.
大约10年前 菲尔挑战我跟他赛跑
Maybe 10 years ago, Phil challenged me to a race.
真不敢相信
I don't believe it!
爸爸赢了
Daddy wins!
你们相信有奇迹吗
Do you believe in miracles?
大美帝
U.S.A.!
他当时感到很空虚
He was feeling adrift
因为孩子们都回学校去了
because the kids were back at school,
于是我让他跑赢我
so I let him beat me.
从那以后他就说个没完
He has not shut up about it since.
天啊 尤塞恩·博尔特又赢了
Oh, my God, Usain Bolt wins again!
你能想象那是什么感觉吗
Can you even imagine what that feels like?
我不用想象 亲爱的
Oh, I don't have to, sweetheart.
我亲身经历过
I lived it.
本来我好像输定了
All appeared lost,
但我启动后劲发力...
but I turned on the afterburners --
他听过这故事了 菲尔
He's heard the story, Phil.
结果我完成了夫妻赛跑史上
And I pull off one of the greatest upsets
最伟大的反超之一
in the history of husband-and-wife competition.
好吧 我会去参加大学面试
Okay, I'll go to that college interview
听他们说完
and hear them out.
我为你感到骄傲 哥们
I'm proud of you, buddy.
我们刚才所做的
I think what you and I did right there
应该就是传说中的"好家教"
was called "great parenting".
跑步故事也许是时候退出历史舞台了
Might be time to retire that story.
真抱歉
I am so sorry.
我刚才太迟钝了
That was insensitive.
没意识到重温那场失败
I didn't realize how much it must bother you
会让你多么不爽
to relive that loss.
菲尔 我只是觉得...
Phil, I am just feeling --
不许你说自己是"废物"
Hey, don't you dare call yourself "a failure".
我让你赢的
I let you win.
什么
You what?
我其实能轻松跑赢你
Oh, I had you beat, easily.
那次我大汗都没流一滴
I didn't even break a sweat.
事实上
As a matter of fact,
为了忍住不发力 我还差点拉伤了肌肉
I almost pulled a muscle holding back.
但我看出来那对你有多重要
But, I saw how much it meant to you,
于是我让你赢了
and I let you win.
是啊
Oh, wow, yeah.
很合理啊 我懂的
No, that makes a lot of sense. I get it.
就像其他马
Like the way all the other horses
希望"秘书"好过些一样
wanted Secretariat to feel good.
现在你成"秘书"了
Now you're Secretariat?
我不知道
I don't know.
"秘书"有娶了一个疯子吗
Was Secretariat married to a crazy person?
天啊 菲尔 百分百是我让你赢的
Oh, God, Phil, I 100% let you win.
那你也百分百可以再赢我啊
Then, you could 100% beat me again.
我当然可以 同样的路线吗
Oh, I could. Same course?
我比那时更强壮了
I've only gotten stronger.
我们再多加几个挑战怎么样
How 'bout we add a few challenges?
攀架
Monkey bars?
太棒 爬绳
Great! Rope climb.
我爱 轮胎
I love it. Tires.
有何不可 中午进行
Why not? Noon?
行 我要带人看房 但我可以移期
Fine. I have a showing. I'll move it.
希望你的身躯也还移得动啊
Hope it's not too heavy.
随警巡逻的授权表真是
The release form for this ride-along is --
详尽得惊人啊
is shockingly thorough.
我不会让你们遇到任何危险
I'm not gonna let anything happen to you.
我不想再埋葬一个随警巡逻员了
I can't bury another ride-along.
我是这个辖区的笑料
I'm kind of the precinct cut up.
好了 米奇尔 不会有事的
Okay. Mitchell, it'll be fine.
他们天天干这个
They do these things all the time.
你倒说得轻巧
Yeah, easy for you to say.
我的脑袋跟某黑帮专属色撞色
My entire head is a gang color.
这真是太令人兴奋了
Okay, this is so exciting.
你知道吗 我上辈子
You know, in my alternate life,
就是个警察
I'm a -- I'm a cop.
你上辈子不是
I-I thought that your alternate life
教迷途少年跳街舞的吗
was you teaching at-risk youth to street dance.
不 我是教他们通过跳街舞
No, I teach them to believe in themselves
学会相信自己
through street dance.
小卡总想去随警巡逻
Cam's always wanted to go on a ride-along.
于是我叫我
So, I called in a favor
在地检署上班的法学院朋友露西帮忙
to my law school friend Lucy at the DA's office.
奇怪的是 他们部门缺人
Weird thing, they're understaffed.
她邀我去当检察官
And she offered me a job as a prosecutor.
我想象不出自己戴检察官徽的样子
I just -- I can't picture myself with a badge.
毕竟我已经痛恨我钱包有多厚了
I mean, I already hate how thick my wallet is.
我们什么时候撇了
So, when do we roll?
-你是指出发吗 -收到
- You mean leave? - Oh, copy that.
我很难忍住不说行话
You know, it's hard for me not to use the lingo.
我自己也算是法界先锋
Bit of a lawman myself,
在高中担任代理副校长
acting high-school vice principal.
他们给我取名号"关节炎"
Anyway, they call me "arthritis"
因为我不让高四学生[老年人]好过
because I make life hard on seniors.
没人这么叫你
They don't.
但他自己做了名牌放到办公桌上 对吧
But he did make a sign for his desk, didn't ya?
你不觉得你有点用力过猛了吗
Do you think that perhaps you're coming on a tad strong?
不 我认为斯塔勃利斯基警官
No, I think Officer Stablitzky
会很欣赏我懂行话
appreciates me knowing the language.
就像去意大利时
It's, like, when you go to Italy,
每两个字中间插句"甭客气"[意语]
you use "prego" every other word.
-他们特喜欢 -非法闯入现行
- They love it. - Break-in in progress.
库伯与奥林匹克街
Cooper and Olympic.
-等等 她说什么 -现行
- Wait. What was that? - In progress?
我们该等他们犯完案再去吗
Should we wait 'til they're done?
-12A3响应 -收到 12A3
- 12-A-3 responding. - Copy 12-A-3.
米奇尔 不如你坐副驾驶吧
Mitchell, why don't you ride shotgun?
不 他坐激流勇进时
Oh, no, You know, he doesn't do that well
在前排吓坏了 所以...
on Splash Mountain in the front seat, so...
他不会有事的 上车
He'll be fine. Get in.
遵命 警官 好的
Yes, sir. Okay.
那好 那或许
Okay, and then, you know, then,
每一个案子我俩轮换坐前座
maybe I can front seat on even crimes.
-这样才公平 -还是不要了
- You know, to keep it fair. - Probably not.
菲尔 现在退出还不迟
You know, Phil, it's not too late to back out.
我的身体状况在人生巅峰
I am in the best shape of my life.
上次去体检后
After my last physical,
医生把我的应激试验结果发到社交网站上了
the doctor posted my stress test on his Instagram.
亲爱的 我每周去篮球场锻炼四天
Honey, I'm on the basketball court four days a week.
他们都叫我"菲尔·灌篮菲人"
They call me "Phil Dunk-phy".
你好好看看我的脸
Well, take a good look at this face
因为你接下来只能看到我的后脑勺了
'cause it's the last time ou're gonna see it for a while --
各就各位 预备 跑
on your mark, get set, go!
我立即拉伤了肌肉
I immediately pulled that muscle
就是从头顶
that runs from the top of your head
一直到脚底的那条
down to the bottom of your feet.
事实是
The truth is,
我被夹在工作和不想去健身之间
between work and not wanting to workout,
所以根本没怎么去健身
I hadn't worked out that much.
欢迎来到丛林 克莱尔
Welcome to the jungle, Claire.
猴哥一盯上你 猴哥...
Monkey see, monkey d-
我的第一反应是我的双肩都中弹了
My first thought was that I had been shot in both shoulders.
是这样的 在克莱尔去健身时
Here's the thing -- while Claire works out,
我的确去了篮球场
I do go to the basketball court,
但是去参加机器人大战
but, uh, for epic robot battles.
旋转争霸者又将我堵死了
Oh, Spin-a-tron cornered me again.
看来我被你消灭了
Looks like you got me dead --
负鼠拳
Possum-punch!
负鼠拳 负鼠拳
Possum-punch! Possum-punch!
云朵看起来有点不妙
Clouds look kind of ominous, huh?
好像有雨滴到我身上了
Kind of felt a raindrop.
-或许我们该改天再... -好
- Maybe we should res- - Okay.
抱歉我们没赶上抢劫
Sorry we missed that robbery.
要能那样开始一天该多带劲
It would've been a fun way to start the day.
你们有没有考虑过用导航应用
Yeah, hi. Have you guys considered using the Waze app.
我可以打开
I could fire it up
然后做你们的引路鹅
and it'd be kind of, like, your Goose.
-你看到了吗 -看到什么
- Whoa, did you see that? - See what?
我被挡住了 什么都看不见
I'm blocked. I can't see anything.
那个混蛋刚刚超了那位婆婆的车
That jerk just cut off that old lady.
-想吓唬他一下吗 -吓唬谁
- Wanna mess with him? - Mess with who?
这样合规矩吗
Is that allowed?
他能怎么办 报警吗
What's he gonna do, call the cops?
你们能大点声说话吗
Can you speak up a little bit?
我跟不上了
I'm losing the thread.
警笛在那
That's the siren.
-好的 -先别开
- Okay. ?- Not yet.
别开
Not yet.
现在
Now!
我的天
Oh, my God!
他慌了 他靠边停了
He's freaked out. Oh, he's pulling over.
-戴上墨镜瞪他 -好的
- Put these on and glare at him. - ?Okay, okay.
没错 你知道你犯错误了
That's right. You know you were bad.
像狗一样坐那反省去
Sit in your shame like a dog!
你天生是这块料
?You're a natural.
我的天 太爽了
Oh, my God, that was such a rush.
我猜揍人或边跑边接到球
I imagine that's what it feels like to punch a guy or --
就是这种感觉
or catch a ball while running.
两位话痨 注意前方
Oh, hey, Chatty-Cathys, heads up.
-那边可能有代号10-99事项 -什么
- Possible 10-99 right over here. - What?
那边有两个下三滥在做现金交易
Couple low lifes over there exchanging cash-money.
-那边 -因为那是报刊亭
- Right here? ?- That's because it's a newsstand.
我还很确定1099是填报税表时用的
And I'm pretty sure a 1099 is a tax form.
-小卡 -是的 如今干什么都得填表
- Oh, Cam. - Oh, yeah, well, what isn't a form these days?
我都被校董事会的文件活埋了
School board's got me buried in paperwork.
我去上个厕所都得三个人签字批准
I gotta get three John Hancocks just to take a leak.
你瞧 我们是一样的
We're the same, see?
容我打断一下
Oh, if I can interrupt for just one second.
我一直在输入车牌号
I've been typing license plates numbers --
你说我可以
as you said I could --
这辆脏车里的这家伙
and this guy in this dirty car here,
正因为未付子女赡养费被缉
he has a warrant for unpaid child support.
很敏锐 阿普里
Good catch, Pritch.
现在他连昵称都有了
He gets a nickname now?!
-贼头鼠脑的 -是啊
- Hmm, looking squirrely. - Yeah.
没错 他逃跑了
Yep, we got a runner!
跟紧我
?Stick by me.
我的天 真要去抓人
Oh, my God, is this happening?
真要去抓人 好的
This is happening. Okay.
两位 两位
Hey, guys? Guys?
后座没有门把手 我也想去
There's no handles back here! I wanna come!
卢克 我读过你的申请论文了
Well, Luke, I read your essay.
你很有勇气
Took a lot of guts to admit
承认一年前没准备好读大学
you weren't ready for college a year ago.
当时我还很不成熟
I had a lot of growing up to do.
于是我找了工作 自己付账单
So, I got a job, I paid my bills,
我上网读华尔街日报
and I read the Wall Street Journal online
直到我看完了五篇免费文章的额度
until I used up my five free articles.
从你的信用评分来看
Well, based on your credit score,
红杉社区大学欢迎你入读
we'd like to welcome you to Sequoia Community College.
谢谢
Thank you!
一旦你走过十五道
And once your walk through
运输安全局认可的金属探测器
one of our 15 TSA-approved metal detectors,
一切皆有可能
anything is possible.
课业很难吗
How hard is it?
我们的大多数学生
Well, most of our students report
每周做十到十五小时的
about 10 to 15 hours of homework a week
课后作业
in addition to class time.
听起来像正经大学似的
That sounds like real college.
这就是正经大学
This is a real college.
需要付出很多努力
And it's a lot of hard work.
但你在这里用功两年
But, you put in your two years here,
然后转学到正经...
then transfer to a real --
到四年制大学
to a four-year college
就能找到入门级工作
and you will land an entry-level job.
谈不上光鲜
Nothing too glamorous,
但你付出努力 向上爬
but you pay your dues, climb the ladder.
等你四十五岁时
By the time you're 45,
你就能住上三间卧室有栅栏的房子了
you're living in a three-bedroom house with a picket fence!
三间卧室有栅栏的房子
Three-bedroom house with a picket fence?
我家不就是吗
Already got one of those.
在这还能免费洗衣吃饭看有线电视
Plus, free meals, laundry, and cable.
我已经实现梦想了
I am living the dream.
知道我怎么想吗
You know what I say?
"谁需要读大学啊"
"Who needs college?"
刚才做得好 我请你吃甜甜圈
Great work out there. I'm getting you a donut.
你应得的
You earned it.
警察吃甜甜圈 不会太符合刻板印象吗
Er, a donut. Isn't that a little on the nose?
太合胃口才对吧
And a lot on the belly.
勃利斯
Ah, Blitz!
二位 二位
Okay, guys, guys.
后座还是打不开门
The door handle situation really hasn't changed.
-抱歉 -没错
- Oh, sorry. - Yeah.
我给他开门了
I opened it.
警官 算了
Sir? Okay.
太丢人了
So humiliating.
饺子警官就那么把我扔在车后座
Officer Pierogi just banishes me to the backseat
好像我只是搭车一样
like I'm just along for the ride.
这本来就是"随警巡逻"
Well, it is called a "Ride-along". So...
米奇尔
Mitchell!
露西 小卡 这是露西
Oh, hey, Lucy, um -- Cam, this is Lucy.
今天就是她帮我们安排的
She's the one that set all this up for us.
太谢谢你了
Thank you so much.
-米奇尔今天特别开心 -那太好了
- Mitchell had a wonderful time. - Oh, great.
-意思是你同意了吗 -问题是什么
- So, does that mean the answer's "Yes"? - What's the question?
几周来
Oh, I've been trying for weeks
我都在试图说服他当检察官
to get this guy to become prosecutor.
你是说《法律与秩序》中的
Y-- You mean, like, Angie Harmon on --
安吉·哈蒙
on "Law and Order"
或者《洛城法网》中的苏珊·黛
or Susan Dey on "L.A. Law"?
或者做这份工作的男人
Or a man who does that job.
那你怎么没和我说呢
Okay, well, why didn't you tell me about this?
你们先好好讨论吧
I'm going to give you guys a minute.
但是米奇尔 周一之前你得告诉我结果
But, um, Mitchell, I really need to know by Monday.
不然我就得去找别人了 好吗
Otherwise, I have to move on to someone else, okay?
-好 -很高兴见到你
- Okay. ?- It was nice to meet you.
-我也是 -再见
- Nice to meet you. ?- Bye!
很抱歉
Okay, I'm -- I'm sorry
我没和你说这份工作的事
I -- I didn't tell you about the job.
只是这是个重大改变
It's -- it's just a big change,
我希望自己做出这个决定
and I wanted to make this decision on my own.
知道吗 这是好消息
You know what, here's the good news.
-你有个很棒的工作机会 -嗯
- You have a fantastic job offer... ?- Mm-hmm.
如果今天我们学到了什么
...and if today taught us anything,
那就是你对这世界有激情
it's that you have a passion for this world.
实际上 如果今天我们学到了什么
Well, actually, if today taught me anything,
那就是我绝对不想要这份工作
it's that I definitely do not want this job.
我要去找露西
I'm -- I'm gonna go find Lucy.
真好 我迟到了
Oh, good. I'm late.
我在努力不受日程的控制
I'm trying to free myself of the calendar.
我按生物周期节律生活
I live by my circadian rhythms.
真重要
So important!
妮可 这是我外公杰
Nicole, this is my grandfather, Jay.
你好吗
How do you do?
这位是辣酱专家 我妻子歌洛莉亚
And this is the sauce maven herself, my wife, Gloria.
很高兴见到你
Very nice to meet you.
我喜欢你的口音
Oh, I love your accent.
我之前争取了
You know, I was up for the role
墨西哥矮子毒枭情妇的位子
of El Chapo's mistress.
我没看那部电影
Oh, I did not see that movie.
什么电影
What movie?
我们很感激
And we appreciate you taking time
你在繁忙的工作中抽出时间
from your busy schedule here at NERP.
这是个很有活力的组织
It's a dynamite organization.
我是铁杆粉 我喜欢你做的事
I'm a big fan. Love what you're doing.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我在推销 我在这样做
I was selling. That's what I was doing.
我不知道这邪教宣传的是什么理念
I don't know what nonsense this cult was pushing,
但反正最后
but at the end of the day,
他们会参与辣酱生意
they were gonna be in the sauce business.
这些辣椒
And so, these peppers
是歌洛莉亚辣酱的核心
are the heart of Gloria's sauce.
但这是成品
But this is the finished product,
当然
of course --
莎莎辣酱
the Salsa Atomica.
很有辣椒感
Mmm! Peppery!
她有精细的味觉
She has a sophisticated palate!
我能感觉到治愈效果
I can feel the healing.
也许那就是你容光焕发的原因
Maybe that's why you're glowing.
是我疯了 还是她真的容光焕发
Am I crazy or is she glowing?
绝对是容光焕发
Totally glowing!
歌洛莉亚 我发现你有点安静
Gloria, I notice that you're really kind of quiet.
是缺乏维生素D吗
Is that a vitamin D thing?
我们有袜子能解决这一问题
'Cause we have socks that can address that.
不 我只是...
No, I'm just --
让我卖掉这个很难
you know, it's hard for me to sell this.
这在我家族里传了五代
It's been in my family for five generations.
他们大部分15岁就有了孩子
Most of them had kids at 15.
我村里一直很动荡
Things were not always easy in my village.
但我们
But the one thing
一直可以依靠的一样东西就是辣酱
that we could always count on was the sauce
这是由几种神奇的哥伦比亚辣椒混合而成
made from this blend of magical Colombian peppers.
也许是因为
Well, maybe it was just the way
水从山上流下来
the water came down the mountain
在我们的家庭农场周围蜿蜒
and curved around our family farm.
我喜欢山和曲线
I love mountains and curves.
太诺普了
So NERP!
我记得
You know, I remember
我祖母每周日为我做饭
my grandmother cooking for me every Sunday.
我会抓着她的围裙
I would hold on to her apron
跟她在厨房里转来转去
and follow her around the kitchen
而她在准备辣酱
while she prepared her sauce.
她会把勺子送到我嘴边
She would hold out the spoon to me
说 "尝尝
and say, "Taste this.
这是你的家"
It's your familia."
我觉得诺普公司是我家
I feel like NERP is my familia.
是啊 我们圣诞节都在这里过的
Yeah, we were all here on Christmas.
也许现在是时候了
Maybe it is the right time.
我祖母不在了
My abuela is gone.
叔祖母都不在了
My great aunts are all gone.
河道被改直了
They straightened the river.
诺普公司可以重新把它变弯
NERP can re-curve it.
也许是时候跟
Maybe it is the time to say "Goodbye"
唯一一样有真正联系的东西说"再见"了...
to the one thing that is a real connection to --
你不会跟任何东西说再见
You're not saying "Goodbye" To anything.
交易结束了
This deal is done!
很抱歉这样为难你
I'm so sorry to have put you in this position.
我绝对不会让你背弃...
I will never ask you to turn your back --
-你搞砸了 蠢蛋 -什么
- You blew it, you dummy! - What?
我本来想卖掉那白痴辣酱的
I wanted to sell that stupid sauce!
等等 我搞不懂了
Wait a minute. I'm confused.
你为什么要告诉她交易取消了
Why did you tell her that the deal was off?
我是想保护你的家族传承
I was trying to protect your legacy.
什么传承 根本没有传承
What legacy? There's not legacy.
整个故事都是我瞎编来抬高价格的
I invented that whole story to drive up the price.
你确定你是销售业的吗
Are you sure you're in sales?
那照片呢
What about the pictures?
是我从曼尼的
I cut them out
《国家地理》旧杂志上剪下来的
from Manny's National Geographic old magazines.
瞧瞧 这里甚至还有
Look, there's even a picture
环球影城游玩的照片
at the Universal Studios tour.
背景是《惊魂记》的房子
That's the "Psycho" House in the back!
所以你想摆脱辣酱生意吗
So, you want to get rid of the business?
是啊 我讨厌它
Yes, I hate that sauce.
像狗一样烦
It's a dog!
我在市里有好多储存室
I have storage lockers all over town
里面都是辣酱罐
full of jars.
我试过冲进马桶 但它腐蚀了管道
I tried to flush it, but it eats up the pipes.
你可以直接告诉我啊
You could've just told me.
我不想承认你是对的
I didn't want to admit that you were right
我这辈子都得听你说
and have to hear "I told you so"
"我跟你说过了吧"
for the rest of my life.
是你这辈子
Well, your life.
但这是我结婚后自己做的
But, it was the first thing I was doing on my own
第一个事业
after getting married.
结果很失败
And it was a failure.
亲爱的 你别把自己逼太紧
Honey, you've got to cut yourself some slack.
你知道我抛弃过多少
Do you know how many ideas I had to dump
行不通的点子吗
because they weren't working?
我曾是职业回力球联赛的隐名合伙人
I was a silent partner of a professional Jai Alai league.
是用汤勺玩球的那项运动吗
With the ball and the scoopy thing?
你俩 搞什么呢
You guys! What was that?!
现在我再也没法得到我自己的豆袋椅了
Now I'm never gonna get my own bean bag chair.
不 现在没事了 我们想卖了
No, it's gonna be fine. We want to sell now.
太迟了 她翻篇了
It's too late. She's moved on.
妮可不给第二次机会
Nicole doesn't give second chances.
主要是因为《第二次机会》是
Mostly because that's the name
她和安德鲁·麦卡锡失败的浪漫喜剧的名字
of a failed rom-com she made with Andrew McCarthy.
我之前就是在那部剧上看到的她
That's where I've seen her before!
听着 这还没结束
Listen, this isn't over.
我之前有过背水一战的时候
I've had my back against the wall before.
丹佛 橱柜展览会 97年
Denver, Closet-Con, '97.
我仓库里都是雪松货架
I had a warehouse full of cedar shelves.
落基山脉刮来一场风暴
A storm blew in over the Rockies --
你卖了橱柜 我知道
You sold the closet. I get it.
-我们上去吧 -故事情节还有很多的
- Let's go up there. - There's a whole story here.
妮可 瞧瞧谁回来了
Nicole! Look who came back!
我们刚在外面交谈
Listen, we were just talking outside,
也许我有点轻率了
and maybe I was a little rash.
真的吗
Really?
也许太轻率[皮疹]了
Maybe a big rash.
很高兴听你这样说
I'm so happy to hear you say that
你们走后我一直
'cause I haven't been able to stop
忍不住吃你们的辣酱
eating your salsa since you left.
你没有办法证明是吃了我们辣酱
There's no way to prove that.
顺便问问
Apropos of nothing,
你信西药吗
do you believe in Western medicine?
爽
Ahh! Sweet.
卢克
Luke!
爸爸
Dad?
很需要你 伙计
Need you bad, buddy.
-你为什么在叫 -别告诉你妈妈
- Why are you yelling? - Oh, don't tell Mom,
我运动过猛 我耳朵都堵了
but I worked out too hard, and it clogged my ears.
我需要一些冰块 还有热敷袋
I need some ice. And a heating pad.
还有止痛药
And some aspirin.
还有不需要嚼的食物 比如果冻或汤
And some soft foods, like Jell-o or soup.
你能做水煮蛋吗 能听到我说话吗
Can you poach an egg? Can you even hear me?!
您好
Hi.
好的
Okay.
-我马上回来 -好吧
- I'll be right back. -Okay...
怎么了
What's going on?
别告诉你爸 但我动不了了
Don't tell you father, but I can't move.
帮我把浴缸放好水 等放好了
Start me a tub and when it's ready,
把我抱到楼上再放进浴缸里
carry me upstairs and put me in it.
你能帮我烧壶水泡茶吗
Can you boil water for tea?
可以吧
I guess.
卢克 你上哪去啦 哥们
Luke, what happened, chief?
我在帮妈弄点东西
Uh, I'm helping Mom with something!
别暴露啊
Don't say that!
克莱尔 没事吧
Claire, everything okay?!
没事啊 我就拉伸一下
Yes! I'm just stretching!
我也是
Me, too!
卢克
Luke!
他来帮忙我弄一些电脑的东西
Uh, he's helping me with something on the computer!
他可会弄电脑了
He's so good at computers!
太聪明了 这孩子
Oh, such a smart boy!
好了 够了 你们俩简直神经病
Okay, all right. This is nuts.
什么 别
What? No.
哎哟喂
Oh, boy.
你好啊
Hi.
-你好啊 亲爱的 -宝贝
- Oh, hi, honey. - Hey, sweetie.
你还好吗
Are you good?
还不错啊
Oh, yeah, yeah.
-那你呢 -棒呆了
- Are you good? - ?So good!
我不知道你们俩是在搞什么鬼
I don't know what's going on here,
但你们俩都不好
but neither of you are good!
如果你们想要有人照顾你们
If you want someone to take care of you,
我建议等你们俩能动了 再生个孩子吧
I suggest once you can move, you make another baby.
你也浑身疼吗
You're hurting, too?
那场比赛可真是要亲命了
That race, it almost destroyed me.
我可能这辈子只能维持这个姿势了
And I have to spend the rest of my life in this position.
我们这是在干嘛啊
What are we doing?
我们这比赛的状态就像两个不中用的中年人
We're competing like a couple of 40-year-olds.
我好几个月没健身了
I haven't worked out in months.
但你这是怎么回事
But, what's up with you?
你不是整天往篮球场跑吗
You're out on that basketball court all the time.
克莱尔
Claire.
我想介绍你认识一个人
There's someone I'd like for you to meet...
这是牛逼负鼠哥
This is Awesome Possum.
我不是去运动
Instead of working out,
我都是跟超酷的朋友们玩机器人大战
my super cool friends and I have epic robot battles.
我唯一会流汗的时候
The only time I break a sweat
是我们跑去买冰淇淋的时候
is when we run after the ice cream truck.
半途而废的感觉就是这样吗
Is this what giving up feels like?
不算 我们一起放弃就不算啊
No, not if we do it together.
我们一起用合理的速度
Let's boldly walk forward at a reasonable pace
大步迈进
into this new future
这个不用假装我们还宝刀未老的未来
where we don't have to pretend to be strong or fast.
-我能坦白一件事吗 -可以啊
- Can I make a confession? - Yeah.
有时候我会下午五点就饿了
Sometimes, I get hungry at, like, 5:00.
我也是啊
Me, too!
我们开始提早吃晚饭吧
Let's start having early dinners!
那时间太合理了
It makes so much sense.
老人家太聪明了
Old people are wise.
不行 负鼠哥 不行
Oh, no, Poss! No!
不行 我给了你生命
No! I gave you life!
佩里博士 我是卢克·邓菲
Dr. Perry, this is Luke Dunphy.
忘了我之前说的话吧
Forget what I said.
我想要今天就开始上大学
I'd like to start college today.
别啊 卢克
No! Luke!
米奇尔 进来
Mitchell, come in here.
小房间 大镜子 手铐
Wow. Small room, big mirror, handcuffs.
饮品超贵
Overcharge for drinks,
这里很可能是西好莱坞的情趣酒吧呢
and this could be a bar in West Hollywood.
跟我说 你为什么不接这份工作
Okay, why aren't you taking this job?
-我不想啊 -为什么
- I don't want to. - ?Why not?
你不喜欢自由职业 你几乎都没在做
You hate freelancing. You're barely doing it.
我还挺忙的呢
I-I'm plenty busy.
是吗 因为其实呢
Are you? Because you know what?
我跟莉莉看到你
Lily and I saw you
往口袋里放面包屑
putting breadcrumbs in your pocket the other day.
你是不是又开始下午没事干
Are you back to spending your afternoons
就跑去公园喂鸽子了 米奇尔
with the pigeons in the park, Mitchell?
什么 它们饿嘛
W-- You know, they're hungry.
不 是你饥肠辘辘
No, you're hungry.
急需人生目标补充
For a purpose.
就觉得不适合我嘛
It's just not my thing.
坐下
Sit down. ?
不适合你是吗
Not your thing, huh?
看好了 这是我今天下午抓拍的你
Okay, well, I snapped this picture of you this afternoon.
你认出了这张照片里的人吗
Do you recognize the person in this picture?
认出来了 是我 你刚说过啊
Uh, Yes, it's me. You just said that, so...
好的 那你看看你脸上是什么表情
Okay, well, what is the expression on your face?
-你在干嘛 -我问了你问题
- What are you doing? - I asked a question!
"你脸上是什么表情"
"What is the expression on your face?"
是在笑
It's a smile.
那你会怎么描述这个"笑"
And how would you describe this..."smile"?
是开怀大笑
Well, from ear-to-ear.
勃利斯基上哪去买我的甜甜圈了
Wh-where's Blitz with my donut?
想吃甜甜圈
You'll get a donut
等我听到我要的答案了你就能吃 你个垃圾
when I get answers, you piece of trash!
我的老天啊 这...
Oh, my gosh, what --
这到底是怎么回事呢
what's happening here, huh?
抱歉 米奇尔 其实呢
I'm sorry, Mitchell. You know what?
我只是来帮你的
I'm just here to help you.
这里就是我们俩谈谈心
Let's just you and me talk.
你是认真的吗 一人分饰好警察坏警察
Are you seriously trying to good cop/bad cop me?
不是 我只是想要了解了解你
No, I'm trying to get some understanding
因为今天一整个下午我都跟你在一起
because I was with you the entire afternoon
而你无法否认你今天玩得很开心吧
and you can't deny you had a great time.
等等 除了...
Wait a minute -- except for when --
除了你下车去追那个人那会儿
when you got out of the car to chase that guy down.
米奇尔 那段时间发生了什么
Mitchell, what happened?
没有啊
Nothing.
我们去追那个不负责任的爸爸时
Okay, we were chasing after that deadbeat guy,
然后我开始 开始想到他的孩子
and I started -- I started thinking about his kid.
我当时就想着抓住他 让他付出代价
And I just -- I wanted to catch him and make him pay.
然后斯塔勃利斯基把他按倒在地
And then, Stablitzky got him on the ground
我看到他的表情 他...
and I saw his face and he was --
他当时在害怕
he was scared.
他也是个活生生的人
There's a person there.
我并不知道事情的全部真相
I don't know the whole story.
我觉得我没办法轻易就把人丢进大牢
I don't think that I can just toss someone into prison.
-米奇尔 别... -你看 所以我不想跟你说
- Mitchell, come... - See? This is why I didn't tell you, okay?
你会批判我
You're judging me.
你就是那种严厉 正义型的人
You're the tough, justice guy,
但我... 我很心软
and I'm just -- I'm soft.
不 你很公正
No, you're fair.
当然啦 你可能很贴心很敏感
And, of course, you can be thoughtful and sensitive.
但你也可以很严厉啊
But you can be tough.
你还记得我们看《狮子王》时 我们前面
You remember the woman in front of us at "Lion King"
一直把包装纸弄出声音的大帽子女人吗
with the candy wrappers and the big, giant hat?
-我对她大爆发啊 -是啊
- Whoo, I went crazy on her. - You sure did.
就是那份激情
And it is that passion
能让你成为一个很棒的检察官
that would make you an amazing prosecutor.
-你真这么觉得吗 -当然啦
- Do you really think so? - Of course.
而且世界上也没有
And nothing would thrill me more
比起你迈向人生新篇章
than to watch you embark
更让我激动不已的事情了
on this new chapter of your life.
但... 但薪水会少非常多
It is -- it is a lot less money, though.
我们也不着急今天就得做决定嘛
Well, you know, we don't have to decide today.
两位
Guys.
两位 你们又把我落下了
Guys! You forgot me again.
我也想吃炸玉米饼
I'd like tacos too.
米奇尔
Mitchell.
Mitchell!
海莉
Haley.
请进来我办公室一下
In my office please.
来了
Coming.
好吧
Okay.
你在哪里呢
Where are you.
我的脸出事了
Something happened to my face.
我去
I got...
我去吧
I got it.
它去
He's got it.